Guide to the Yale Collection of American Literature Letter Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- "H"
  - HAYNE, PAUL HAMILTON, 1830-1886, 7 (Box 13, Folder 499-505)
    - Leaf-Language of the Pine: original ms, signed, of poem printed under title of "The Pine's Mystery"
      With note in the hand of his son, William H. Hayne, explaining change of title
      Removed from: Za copy of his Poems, Boston, 1882
    - ALS addressed "My dear Sir" [to William Rounseville Alger], "Copse Hill," Augusta, Ga., 1881 May 9
    - ANS to [Hezekiah] Butterworth, Copse Hill, Augusta, Ga., 1879 November 27
      Removed from: Za copy of his Avolio, Boston, 1860
    - ALS to Edwin Percy Whipple, New Haven, 1853 September 6
      In Za copy of his Poems, Boston, 1855, with presentation inscription
    - ALS to Edwin Percy Whipple, Charleston, S. C., 1859 September 10
    - ALS to Edwin Percy Whipple, "Copse Hill," Augusta, Ga., 1872 March 13
      Removed from: Za copy of his Sonnets, Charleston, 1857, with presentation inscription
    - ALS to unknown correspondent [in Albany, N. Y.], Augusta, Ga., 1875 April 18
      Removed from: Za copy of his Lives of R. Y. Hayne and H. S. Legaré, Charleston, 1878
    - ALS to unidentified correspondent, Charleston, 1860 May 8
      Removed from: Za copy of his Mountain of the Lovers, New York, 1875
    - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton (1812- 1883). ALS to Paul Hamilton Hayne, Crawfordsville, Ga., 1872 October 10
      [Includes annotated typed copy]
    - ALS to Mr. Butterworth, Copse Hill, Ga., 1886 January 2
    - ALS to [Bayard Taylor], Augusta, Ga.
      [1] p.
      Concerning a request for his photograph
      Acquired on exchange (from Germ. Lit. Coll.) November. 1967
    - ALS addressed "My dear Sir" [to John Esten Cooke], Charleston, S. C., 1856 September 16
      2 pages with envelope
      Removed from: Za copy of "Russell's Magazine," v. I, April. 1857, edited by P. H. Hayne
  - HAYNE, WILLIAM H. (Box 13, Folder 506)
    - Repentant, AMS
      Poem of four lines
  - HEARN, LAFCADIO, 1850-1904 (Box 13, Folder 507)
    - 4 ALS to the publisher T. Hasegawa, 1895, 1899, undated
      1 page, 1 page (with env.), 1 page, 2 pages
      Removed from: Za copies of his Chin Chin Kobakama, Goblin spider, The old woman who lost her dumplings, and The boy who drew cats, respectively
    - 3 ALS to Messrs. Ticknor, New Orleans, La. and [n. p.], 1885, undated
      1 page, 2 pages, and 1 page respectively
      Removed from: the Za copies of his Some Chinese ghosts (1887) and Chita (1889)
    - ALS to Roberts Bros., New Orleans, [1882 February]
      Removed from: Za copy of his Youma (1890)
    - 4 ALS to Messrs. Osgood, New Orleans, 1884, [1884]
      1 page, 2 pages, 2 pages, 1 page respectively
      Removed from: Za copy of his Stray leaves (1894)
    - ALS to Guy M. Carleton, Tokyo, Japan, 1898 December 19
      Gift of Mrs. Guy M. Carleton, January 1939
  - HELBURN, THERESA, 1887-1959 (Box 13, Folder 508)
    - TLS to John Gassner, New York, N. Y., 1959 April 28
      With TL (carbon) from John Gassner to Miss Helburn, 1959 May 4, 1 page
      Gift of John Gassner, January. 1960
  - HENRY-RUFFIN, M. E. (MARGARET ELLEN), d. 1941 (Box 13, Folder 509)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Mobile, Ala., 1902 July 14
  - HERNE, JULIE A. (Box 13, Folder 510)
    - 11 TLS to John (Waldhorn) Gassner, New York, N. Y., 1954 April-August
      With an ALS from Mr. Gassner to Mr. Babb, 2 April 1957, concerning Miss Herne and her family
  - HEYWARD, DUBOSE, 1885-1940 (Box 13, Folder 511)
    - TLS to (Sir) J(ohn) C(ollings) Squire, Editor, The London Mercury [192-?], Charleston, S. C.
      Written as Secretary of the Poetry Society of South Carolina, enclosing the Southern number of Poetry, a magazine of verse
      Squire was ed. November. 1919-Sep. 1934 Plain fund, June 1954
  - HICKEY, AGNES MACCARTHY (Box 13, Folder 512)
    - MS copies, with explanatory notes, of ten poems, published in her Out of Every Day
      10 pages
      Gift of the author, November 1943
    - Poems. Ms copies of 3 poems, signed, including: The Home of Emily Dickinson, Amherst; Emily Dickinson's Grave, West Cemetery, Amherst; John James Audubon
      Gift of Agnes MacCarthy Hickey, 1952
  - HIGGINSON, ELLA, 1862-1940 (Box 13, Folder 513)
    - ALS to Mr. Williams, Bellingham, Washington, 1904 March 21
  - HILDRETH, MATTIE OLIVE (Box 13, Folder 514)
    - For Miss Morrison: typewritten copy of poem, Cape May, 1919 July 20
      Removed from: her Sunshine, a book of poems [Camden, N. J.] 1925
  - HILLWAY, TYRUS
    See: MELVILLE, HERMAN, 1819-1891
  - HILLYER, ROBERT, 1895-1961, 2 (Box 13, Folder 515-516)
    - Obsolete Liner: typewritten copy of poem, with author's MS corrections Obsolete Liner: galley-proof, initialed by author
    - Song: typewritten copy of poem Song: galley-proof, initialed by author
    - TLS to Prof. Jack R. Crawford [incomplete], n. p., undated
      Gift of Prof. J. R. Crawford
    - As One Who Bears Beneath His Neighbor's Roof. Signed, dated, 1950 October 19
  - HITCHCOCK, FREDERICK H. (FREDERICK HILLS), 1867-1928 (Box 14, Folder 517)
    - ALS to E(dmund) C(larence) Stedman, New York, N. Y., 1902 October 3
      Removed from: The Imperial Republic by Crane, Elizabeth Green. New York [1902]
  - HITCHWELL, ROSWELL D. (Box 14, Folder 518)
    - ALS to Mr. [Edmund Clarence] Stedman, 44 West 20th St., [New York], 1875 November 11
      Gift of James H. Penniman, May 6, 1921
  - HOFFMAN, CHARLES FENNO, 1806-1884, 2 (Box 14, Folder 519-520)
    - ALS to Abraham Hart, Offices Literary World, [New York, N. Y.], [1845]
      Removed from: His Winter in the West...New York, 1835
    - ALS to Col. Thomas Aspinwall, New York, 1841 September 8
      Removed from: His Greyslaer... New York, 1840
    - ALS to Kenneth Keese, Wednesday morning, [n. p.], undated
      Removed from: His Poems...Phila., 1873
    - The Lakes of New York. 4 lines from "The vigils of faiths," AMS, "To Pomroy Jones, Esq."
    - ALS to Col. (Thomas) Aspinwall, New York, N. Y., 1839 January 16
  - HOLLAND, J. G. (JOSIAH GILBERT), 1819-1881, 3 (Box 14, Folder 521-523)
    - Contract for lease of Holland's house to Charles H. Yates, Springfield, [Mass.], 1868 May 1
      Signed by Holland and Yates
      Removed from: his Plain talks...1806
    - Modern Preaching: original ms, written on half-sheets of paper
      Bought with the Alvord fund, October 1939
    - What the Centennial Ought to Accomplish: original ms, written on half-sheets of paper, and signed at conclusion of text
    - 2 ALS to Miss Daggett, New York, 1876 October, December
    - ALS to George Alfred Townsend, Springfield, Mass., 1871 March 25
      Removed from: his Marble prophecy ...New York, 1872
    - The Lesson of the Year: Original ms
      10 numbered leaves
      Edited for publication in Century magazine under heading "Topics"
      Purchased with other Holland ms material from Black. Alvord, 1959
    - Old and Blind: Original ms
      Poem of nine 4-line stanzas; unsigned. Edited for publication
      in Scribner's
    - Poverty as a Discipline: Original ms
      4 numbered leaves
    - ALS to Seth H. Clark, Springfield, Mass., 1846 November 27
      Concerning the engraving of a masthead for his newspaper to be issued 1 January 1847
      Newspaper failed after 6 months
      Purchased with other Holland ms material from Black. Alvord fund
    - ALS to Mr. King [?], New York, N. Y., 1876 September 28
      Concerning a picture to be engraved by King's firm, probably for Scribner's magazine
    - ALS to Mr. Westcott, New York, N. Y., 1879 May 23
      Concerning the papers for a boat which Holland had sold to Westcott
      Purchased from Black with other Holland ms material, 1959
    - ALS to "Dear Friend," New York, N. Y., 1876 April 17
    - ALS to "Dear Madame," New York, N. Y., 1878 February 6
      Concerning mss submitted to Scribner's Monthly
    - ALS to Mr. Elwell, Springfield, 1866 November 9
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," New York, N. Y., 1874 March 4
      Concerning files of The Spectator
  - HOLLEY, HENRY WHITCOMB, 1827-1897 (Box 14, Folder 524)
    - ALS to E(dmund) C(larence) Stedman, Spokane, Washington, 1892 April 3
      Removed from: his The race problem and other critiques. Buffalo, 1891
  - HOLMES, MARY JANE, 1825-1907, 3 (Box 14, Folder 525-527)
    - Sister Nettie, Original ms: The first leaf of the manuscript
      Purchased, Matthiessen fund, 1958
    - ALS to H. P. R. Holt, Blockport, N. Y., undated
      Written, apparently, in answer to a request for an autograph
    - ALS to Mr. Ambler, Paris, France, 1889 May 21
      Sending her autograph
  - HOLST, HERMANN EDUARD VON, 1841-1904
    See: VON HOLST, H. (HERMANN), 1841-1904
  - HOOD, TOM, 1835-1874 (Box 14, Folder 528)
    - ALS to Frederick Locker-Lampson, London, Eng., [1870 ]
      With a ms note by Locker-Lampson, signed with initials, concerning the subject of the letter. Contains a reference to Joaquin Miller.
      Anon. gift, July 1954
      Tinker 1235
  - HOOVER, HERBERT, 1874-1964 (Box 14, Folder 529)
    - TLS to S. S. Van Dine [pseud. for Willard Huntington Wright], Washington, D. C., 1929 June 1
  - HOPKINS, JOHN HENRY, 1820-1891 (Box 14, Folder 530)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, N. Y., 1891 June 22
  - HOPKINSON, CORINNA PRENTISS (Box 14, Folder 531)
    - ALS to her "Aunt Lydia," Boston, 1850 February 7
      Gift of Mrs. George Pierce Baker, May 1942
  - HOVEY, RICHARD, 1864-1900, 2 (Box 14, Folder 532-533)
    - Forward. Henry George, 29 October 1897 AMS
      20-line poem
    - ALS to Herbert S. Stone, Paris, 1896 January 31
  - HOW, ASHLEY P. (Box 14, Folder 534)
    - ALS to "Friend Coburn," Concord, Mass., 1903 December 1
      Concerns prices on 1st editions of Longfellow's Hiawatha and Cooper's Ways of the Hour
  - HOWARD, BRONSON, 1842-1908 (Box 14, Folder 535)
    - ALS to Mr. Elwood, 101 W. 48th St., June 20
      Mounted on sheet
    - Page 5 of an ALS expressing his appreciation of the efforts made by the management of the Union Square Theatre in New York City in presenting his play, "The Banker's Daughter" in September 1878 - Lotos Club, December 4, 1878
  - HOWARD, SIDNEY COE, 1891-1939 (Box 14, Folder 536)
    - 4 ALS and 1 TLS to Edward Knoblock, Wiscasset, Me., New York, N. Y., [etc], [1926]-1928
  - HOWELLS, WILLIAM COOPER, 1807-1894 (Box 14, Folder 537)
    - 3 ALS to Thomas Gregg, Jefferson, Ohio, 1872, 1887
      Printed letter with autograph address, opening sentence, and signature, to Thomas Gregg, Jefferson, Ohio, January 7, 1887
      Removed from: Za copy of his Recollections of Life in Ohio, Cincinnati, 1895
  - HOWLAND, MARIE (STEPHENS) (Box 14, Folder 538)
    - ALS to E(dmund) C(larence) Stedman, [n. p.], [1874] November 17
      Removed from: her Papa's own girl, New York, Boston, 1874
  - HOXIE, JOHN A. (Box 14, Folder 539)
    - ALS to his aunt Isabella Hoxie, Brook Farm, 1845 August 31
      With letter from the donor to Gilbert Troxell, April 18, 1947
      Gift of Herbert Wood, May 1947
  - HUBBARD, ELBERT, 1856-1915, 2 (Box 14, Folder 540-541)
    - ALS to William Fowler Hopson, East Aurora, 1897 January 15
      Gift of Mrs. W. F. Hopson, 1938
    - ANS to [William Fowler] Hopson, East Aurora, N. Y., 1897 April 8
      Gift of Mrs. Hopson, 1938
    - ALS to Henry Blackwell, N. Y., 1897 April 15
      Removed from: his An interesting personality...Za.H861.902i
    - ALS to Miss Morgan, East Aurora, N. Y., 1896 November 27
    - TLS to George P(hilip) Hambrecht, East Aurora, N. Y., 1902 November 18
  - HUCKEL, OLIVER, 1864-1940 (Box 14, Folder 542)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Baltimore, Md., 1900 December 4
  - HUGHES, RUPERT, 1872-1956 (Box 14, Folder 543)
    - 3 ALS and 1 TLS to Bernhard Knollenberg, Los Angeles, 1942-1943
      Together with various typewritten enclosures, and carbon copies of Mr. Knollenberg's replies
  - HULME, KATHRYN, 1900-1981, 2 (Box 14, Folder 544-545)
    - 7 ALS and 37 TLS to Donald C. Gallup, Kapaa, Kaui, Hawaii, 1977-1980
      56 leaves, various sizes
      With envelopes and enclosures
    - Gallup, Donald C. 47 TL (carbons) to Kathryn (C.) Hulme, New Haven, Connecticut, 1975-1980
      47 leaves, various sizes
  - HUME, CYRIL, 1900-1966 (Box 14, Folder 546)
    - "The Iron Cat" (1933), Typescript (carbon)
      4 leaves, 76 numb l., 1 leaf,
      35 numbered leaves
      A play in two acts
      I. Tomlinson, D. G., joint author
  - HUNEKER, JAMES, 1857-1921, 3 (Box 14, Folder 547-549)
    - 10 ALS and 3 APCS to W(illard) H(untington) Wright, New York, N. Y. and London, Eng., 1913-1917
      With 3 original envelopes, and an ALS from Mrs. Huneker to Mr. Wright, March. 2, 1916
    - In Praise of Unicorns, Typescript (original), signed, and with many ms corrections
      4 leaves
      Sent to W(illard) H(untington) Wright
    - ALS to Mr. Mackay, Marienbad, Austria, 1904 September 13
  - HUNN, FLORA LOUISE SMITH, 1870- (Box 14, Folder 550)
    - Rainbows and Other Poems: Typewritten ms of book of poems, privately printed, under the direction of the Yale Press, 1935
      vi, 2 numbered leaves, 40 numbered leaves
      Gift of the author
  - HUNT, THEODORE W. (THEODORE WHITEFIELD), 1844-1930 (Box 14, Folder 551)
    - ANS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Princeton College, 1890 February 28
      Removed from: his Studies in Literature and Style...New York, 1890
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Princeton, [N. J.], 1887 February 19
  - HURST, FANNIE, 1889-1968 (Box 14, Folder 552)
    - Zora Hurston: A Personality Sketch, Typescript (original)
      [1], 7 numbered leaves
      With ms corrections and revisions by the author. Published in the Yale University Library Gazette, July 1960
      With 2 TLS and 1 ANS to Donald Gallup (Editor of the Gazette), and carbon copies of 5 letters from Mr. Gallup to Miss Hurst
      From the Gazette files
  - HUTTON, LAURENCE, 1843-1904, 2 (Box 15, Folder 553-554)
    - ALS to Miss Annie Burr Jennings, [New York, N. Y.], 1891 March 20
      From the library of Miss Jennings, 1939
    - ANS to E. C. Stedman, New York, 1884 January 16
      Gift of James H. Penniman, April 4, 1921
    - 3 ALS to William G. White, New York and Lewiston, Maine, 1896, 1897
    - ALS to "My Fellow Player" [Edwards?], [n. p.], January 11
- "I"
  - I'ANSON, MILES (Box 15, Folder 555)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Newark, N. J., 1891 July 6
  - INGALLS, JEREMY, 1911-, 2 (Box 15, Folder 556-557)
    - An Old Man's Counsel, original ms poem, written in pencil and signed
      Gift of Miss Ingalls, July 1941
    - ALS to Bernhard Knollenberg, Chicago, 1941 July 21
      Gift of Mr. Knollenberg, July 1941
    - The Metaphysical Sword, typewritten copy, prepared for printing
      85 pages
      Gift of the author, October 1941
  - INGERSOLL, ERNEST, 1852-1946 (Box 15, Folder 558)
    - ALS to Mr. Scudder, New Haven, 1883 April 23
  - INGLE, CHARLES, 1926- (Box 15, Folder 559)
    - 5 ALS to Francis H(artman) Markoe, New York and n. p., undated
      Removed from: Markoe's copy of Ingle's The Waters of the End (1953)
  - IRVING, EDWARD, 1792-1834 (Box 15, Folder 560)
    - ALS to Col. Thomas Aspinwall, New York, N. Y., 1833 April 15
  - IRVING, PETER, 1771-1838 (Box 15, Folder 561)
    - ALS to Col. (Thomas) Aspinwall, London, Eng., 1830 September 6
      Removed from: Aldis copy of Washington Irving's Salmagundi (New York, 1807 v. 1) call no. Za.Ir8.807bb
  - IRVING, THEODORE, 1809-1880 (Box 15, Folder 562)
    - ALS to Col. (Thomas) Aspinwall, New York, N. Y., 1835 October 9
  - IVES, JAMES MERRITT, d. 1895 (Box 15, Folder 563)
    - ANS to Miss Annie M. Kirby, enclosing an autograph note of recommendation, Rye, N. Y., 1884 March 8
      Gift of Professor Richard S. Kirby, July 1939
- "J"
  - J., C. H. (Box 15, Folder 564)
    - Hope On - Hope Ever, autograph ms of poem, signed C. H. J., and inscribed "To Hattie, from a Friend"
  - JACOBSON, LIZ (Box 15, Folder 565)
    - That Came Later, typescript (original)
      12 numbered leaves
      Short story, submitted to the Yale Review
      Gift of the Yale Review, November. 11, 1959
  - JAMES, WILLIAM, 1842-1910 (Box 15, Folder 566)
    - ALS to Dr. [Kenneth] Mackenzie, Tamworth Iron Works, N. H., 1890 September 22
      Gift of Mrs. Kenneth Mackenzie, 1950
      Dr. Mackenzie, pastor of the Memorial Church of the Holy Trinity, Westport, Ct.
  - JANVIER, THOMAS ALLIBONE, 1849-1913, 3 (Box 15, Folder 567-569)
    - ANS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, N. Y., 1904 February 4
      Removed from: Za copy of his Dutch Founding of New York, N. Y., 1903 Gift of Owen F. Aldis, 1911
    - ALS to Miss Annie Burr Jennings, [New York, N. Y.], 1891 March 16
      Plain funds, July 1940
    - ALS to "My dear WC [?]", New York, N. Y., 1907 December 5
    - ALS to John Kendrick Bangs, New York, N. Y., 1902 December 23
  - JARVES, JAMES JACKSON, 1818-1888, 2 (Box 15, Folder 570-571)
    Letters from European correspondents were transferred to the Rare Book Room and to the Conn. and Hist. Manuscripts Collection in 1947. For further information see the file of transfer sheets following the main Jarves correspondence file below.
    - Jarves, James Jackson, Collection. Letters, notes, and cards to James Jackson Jarves, from various correspondents., [1851-1887]
    - Curtis, George William. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, North Shore, Staten Island, N. Y., 1864 August 22
      Phelps fund, September 1946
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, Concord, Mass., 1857 October 23
    - Everett, Edward. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, Cambridge, Mass., 1851 August 1
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, Cambridge, Mass., 1855 June 19
    - Moore, Morris. 2 ALS to James Jackson Jarves, Rome, 1870-1871
    - Mountford, William. ANS to James Jackson Jarves, Cambridge, Mass., n. y. December 7
    - Neal, John. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, Portland, Me., 1855 October 3
    - Norton, Charles Eliot. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, Cambridge, Mass., 1867 December 8
    - Phillips, Wendell. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, n. p., 1869 November 11
    - Sumner, Charles. ALS to James Jackson Jarves, Nahant, Mass., 1871 August 19
  - JAY, PETER A. (PETER AUGUSTUS), 1776-1843 (Box 15, Folder 572)
    - Printed form letter to William Young, Sr., New York, N. Y., 1817 December 8
      In connection with the settling of the accounts of Eastburn, Kirk, and Co.
  - JEFFERSON, JOSEPH, 1829-1905 (Box 15, Folder 573)
    - Autograph
    - ANS to [William Winter], New York, N. Y., 1883 October 12
    - ALS to his son Tom Jefferson, Philadelphia, Pa., 1900 November 13
      S. C. G. Watkins (?)
  - JENNINGS, EDWARD (Box 15, Folder 574)
    - A victim of his greed for gold, [a poem]
      Manuscript
      A poem on the sinking of the Titanic and George Widener
  - JEWETT, SARAH ORNE, 1849-1909, 2 (Box 15, Folder 575-576)
    - 8 lines of text copied from Betty Leicester, signed and dated, 1890 April 14
      1 page, 12mo.
      Removed from: her Betty Leicester, Cambridge, 1890
    - 2 ALS to Miss Abby Alger, South Berwick, Me., 1891, 1894
      2 pages, 12mo. and 4 pages, 16mo.
      Removed from: Za copies of her Tales of New England, Cambridge, 1890, and Betty Leicester's English Xmas, New York, 1894, respectively
    - AL in the third person to William A. Baker, South Berwick, Me., 189[4] July 20
      2 pages, 16mo.
      Removed from: Za copy of her Deephaven (1877)
    - ALS to unidentified correspondent [William A. Baker?], Richfield Springs, N. Y., undated
      Removed from: Za copy of her Mate of the daylight, Cambridge, 1884
    - ALS to Mrs. Brooks, Boston, February 3
      Removed from: Za copy of her Country of the Pointed Firs, Cambridge, 1896
    - 2 ALS to Mr. Drake, South Berwick, Me., 1881, 1883
      4 pages, 12mo. and 4 pages, 12mo.
      Removed from: Za copies of her White heron, Cambridge, 1886, and Deephaven, Cambridge, 1894, respectively
    - ALS to Miss Macy, Boston, 1888 January 12
      3 pages, 12mo.
      Removed from: Za copy of her King of Folly Island, Cambridge, 1888
    - ALS to J. R. Osgood, South Berwick, Me.
      3 pages, 8vo.
      Removed from: Za copy of her Deephaven, Cambridge, 1894 (large- paper ed.)
    - ALS to W. L. Sawyer, South Berwick, Me.
      Removed from: Za copy of her Old Friends and New, Boston, 1879
    - ALS to the Rev. George Bainton, St. Augustine, Fla., 1888 April 19
      Gift of the Rev. Roland H. Bainton
    - ALS to Mrs. Loring, South Berwick, Me., 1896 December 29
    - ALS (fragment) to unidentified correspondent, South Berwick, Me., [1881] August 19
      Final page only
  - JOHNSON, HENRY, 1855-1918 (Box 15, Folder 577)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Brunswick, Maine, 1898 April 7
      Removed from: his Where Beauty Is and Other Poems...Brunswick, Maine, 1898
  - JOHNSON, JOSEPHINE WINSLOW, 1910- (Box 15, Folder 578)
    - Hour Before Light: typewritten copy of poem, with the author's signature
      Gift of R. E. Danielson, February
      1941
    - Hour Before Light: galley-proof
  - JOHNSON, R. BRIMLEY (REGINALD BRIMLEY), 1867-1932 (Box 15, Folder 579)
    - ALS to George Redway (firm, publisher), London, Eng., 1898 January 12
  - JOHNSON, REVERDY, 1796-1876 (Box 15, Folder 580)
    - ALS to "My dear Meredith," Washington, D. C., February 21
      [and typewritten copy]
  - JOHNSON, ROBERT UNDERWOOD, 1853-1937, 3 (Box 15, Folder 581-583)
    - 2 ALS, 1 AL (signed in the hand of a secretary), and 4 TLS to General Nathan Kimball, New York, 1887-1888
      15 pages
    - 4 ALS to Clara Anthony, Florence, Italy and New York, 1892-1893
      With addressed envelopes
      From the Reed papers, transferred from the Coe Collection, August 1951
    - Johnson, Katherine (Mrs. R. U.). 5 ALS to Clara Anthony, New York, 1892 [February-November]
      With 4 addressed envelopes
    - ALS to William Winter, New York, N. Y., 1914 October 10
      Thanking him for his praise of Johnson's "Rheims," and sending him a poem by Don Marquis (not enclosed)
  - JOHNSON, ROSSITER, 1840-1931, 3 (Box 15, Folder 584-586)
    - 2 ALS, 1 AL (not signed) to Andrew Keogh, New York, 1921-1922
      With carbons of 2 replies
    - ALS to "My dear Fred," Amagansett, L. I., 1892 June 6
    - ALS to William S. Ingraham, New York, N. Y., 1900 May 17
      Gift of Edward Ingraham
  - JOHNSTON, RICHARD MALCOLM, 1822-1898 (Box 15, Folder 587)
    - ALS to Jos. M. Stoddart, Baltimore, 1890 March 27
  - JONES, HOWARD MUMFORD, 1892- (Box 15, Folder 588)
    - New England Dilemma, typewritten ms with author's corrections
    - New England Dilemma, galley-proofs, with author's ms notes, additions, and corrections
  - JONES, NARD, 1904- (Box 15, Folder 589)
    - TLS to James T(inkham) Babb, Bellevue, Washington, 1940 May 6
  - JONES, THOMAS S. (THOMAS SAMUEL), 1882-1932 (Box 15, Folder 590)
    - ALS to Henrietta C. Bartlett, New York, N. Y., [1906 March 9]
    - The Island: ms copy of his poem, made by him for Miss Bartlett, and enclosed in ALS listed above
      Gift of Miss Bartlett, February 1940
  - JUDD, GERRIT P. IV (Box 15, Folder 591)
    - Copy of a typewritten letter to Mr. Jim Tully, 726 Yale Station, New Haven, Connecticut, 1938 March 14
  - JUDD, SYLVESTER, 1813-1853 (Box 15, Folder 592)
    - The Dramatic Element in the Bible: original ms, Augusta, Me. In another [hand] at head of title: Ms of Sylvester Judd (Atlantic Monthly)
      52 numbered leaves
  - JUDSON, EMILY C. (EMILY CHUBBUCK), 1817-1854 (Box 15, Folder 593)
    - Sonnet to Winter: original ms of poem, signed with the initials of her pseudonym, "Fanny Forrester"
      Gift of Mrs. G. McC. Troxell, 1933
- "K"
  - KAYE, JOHN BRAYSHAW, b. 1841 (Box 16, Folder 594)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Calmar, Iowa, 1895 September 27
      Removed from: his Vashti... New York, London, 1894